Guide to the Pacific University Boxerettes Collection 1936-1971
Pacific University Archives
Pacific University Boxerettes Collection
1936-1971
MS.50
Pacific University, Archives http://www.pacificu.edu/library/services/archives/ 2043 College Way Forest Grove, OR, 97116 503-352-1405 archives@pacificu.edu
1.0 cubic foot 1 box
The Boxerettes were a women's honorary service group made up of Pacific University students. This collection includes both records and objects from the group such as their constitution, meeting minutes, treasury logs, photographs and original letterman sweater.
Boxerettes (Pacific University Club)
Collection is open for research.
No accruals are expected.
The collection includes the Boxerettes' original constitution, meeting minutes, activities records and treasury logs. It also includes the gavel used at every meeting, an original letterman sweater, a commendation plaque honoring the group for their service work, and other items.
Historical Note
The Boxerettes were an honorary service women's group at Pacific University. The group was founded in 1936 and was active until 1971. Young Pacific women were chosen to be in the Boxerettes based on scholarship, leadership quality and personality. The group helped host such functions as the President's Tea, freshman orientation, the Music in May concert, and beach days with their male counterparts, the Intercollegiate Knights. They were well-known on campus for their visibility in a number of programs and for hosting social events for the student body.
Pacific University; Student activities
Student Life; Women
Minutes
- Records
  - Activities and Review Book, 1951-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boxerette Constitution, Circa 1936-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Boxerette Meeting Minutes, 1948-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Treasury Records, 1946-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Boxerette Songs, Circa 1948-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Information about Collection and Miscellaneous Items, 1936-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Objects
  Objects are placed in the same box as the records, at the end of the collection.
  - Letterman Sweater, Circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1)
  - Gavel, 1936-1971 (Box 1)
  - Commendation Plaque, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Boxerette pins in the shape of dog bones, Circa 1940s-1960s (Box 1)
  - Letterhead Patches, Circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1)